NOEL AMADOR LUNA

www.noelluna.com • noelamadorluna@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/noelamadorluna • github.com/nluna96/

Self-driven and attentive professional with 5+ years of experience in technical client-facing projects. Highly motivated and skilled in building relationships with partners, internal teams, and vendors to achieve desired business outcomes.

CAREER PROJECT HIGHLIGHTS -----

Experian Technical Implementation Guide (Senior Sales Engineer, Experian) Collaborated with Experian Client Solutions Director to enhance, improve transparency, and blueprint the implementation process for Experian clients in an evolving implementation guide. The implementation guide is leveraged in net new and existing integration, which has overall led to fewer implementation errors, a greater understanding of internal and external expectations and requirements, and improved customer satisfaction.

Wells Fargo (Client Technical Analyst, Experian) Technical lead for the Wells Fargo project where I tested and provided feedback to custom API workflows for WF Program Manager. Collaborated with Experian Sales Director, Program Manager, and Sales Engineer to initiate a partnership with Wells Fargo, bringing in 30M over three years.

Discover Financial Services (Technical Solutions Intern, Experian) Worked alongside DFS Product Owner to launch new products. Provided test data, tested APIs, and worked with an internal Project Manager to estimate a launch date for new products. There are about 700K members using services and products I implement.

Work Experience ------

Senior Sales Engineer | Experian Austin, TX

September 2022 - Current

- Work with Sales Directors and Client Executives to bring in 47.6M in new or renewed contracts
- Act as a subject matter expert on Experian Partner Solutions' product suite and data offerings, functioning as a technical liaison among internal clients (Sales, Client Success, Engineering, and Implementation Delivery Teams) and external clients
- Provide subject matter technical expertise through sales presentations and platform demos that provide detailed technical
 information about solution capabilities and competitive differentiation within the Fintech industry
- Maintain a working knowledge of digital technologies, emerging trends, and their applicability to industries and domains that enable you to understand our client's digital transformation priorities, problems, and roadmaps
- Provide feature ideas on products based on client needs and relevant marketplace learnings and work with internal teams to deliver solutions to drive sales

External Strategy Consultant | NTB Survey LTD Darwen, England

June 2022 - September 2022

- Identified and analyzed problems within the organization to develop solutions that are appropriate for the situation
- Consulted with client regarding business operations, organizational culture, leadership, and other aspects of their business that may need improvement
- Developed long-term growth strategies for NTB Survey including identifying potential opportunities and risks involved in each strategy

Client Technical Analyst | Experian Austin, TX

February 2020 - September 2021

- Worked with Sales Directors and Client Success Directors to bring in 35M in new or renewed contracts
- Performed requirements gathering through communication with client and internal teams to build comprehensive implementation solutions for 10+ clients
- Interfaced with product and tech support teams to ensure the smooth deployment of new features and fixes through QA testing and analysis, 100% success of new features deployed

Technical Solutions Intern | Experian Austin, TX

August 2019 - November 2019

- Shadowed Senior Client Technical Analysts through client calls (documented and monitored requirements needed to institute
 proposed updates in relation to customer experience, and provided detailed specifications for proposed solutions including
 time and scope involved)
- Worked alongside internal team to provide test data and QA testing for clients
- Proactively documented new client workflows

Project Coordinator Intern | Experian Austin, TX

May 2019 - August 2019

- Coordinated technical skill trainings for project managers
- Met with project team members to identify and resolve issues
- Worked alongside Senior Project Managers to define project scope, goals, and deliverables
- Met with clients to take detailed ordering briefs and clarify specific requirements for each project

SKILLS -----

Programming: Python, JavaScript (React), Swift

Databases: MySQL, MongoDB

Tools: Git

Languages

Spanish - Native Speaker

English - Full Professional Proficiency

French - Intermediate Mid

Awards -----

- St. Edward's University College Assistance Migrant Program Scholarship recipient (2015-2019)
- Hatton Sumner Scholarship recipient (2016-2019)
- Johnson Turpin Scholarship recipient (2016-2019)

EDUCATION & TRAINING -----

September 2022

The University of Manchester | Manchester, England M.S. Business Analysis and Strategic Management

The University of Texas at Austin | Austin, TX

Data Analysis and Visualization Bootcamp at Texas McCombs

April 2021

St. Edward's University | Austin, TX

B.S. Computer Science & Minor in French

December 2019

Université Catholique de l'Ouest | Anger, France

French language program

July 2017